It's amazing people keep coming to comic book stores...
C'est fou, les gens viennent dans des magasins de BD
...instead ofjust downloading comics digitally.
au lieu de télécharger les BD.
It's probably for the best.
C'est mieux comme ça.
For a lot of these guys, the weekly trip here...
Pendant qu'ils sont ici,
...is the only chance their mom has to go to the basement and change their sheets.
leur mère peut aller changer leurs draps au sous-sol.
Oh, that reminds me, I get fresh sheets tonight. Yay.
Je vais avoir des draps propres ce soir.
Well, what do you think of new comic book night?
Que penses-tu de cette soirée BD ?
Magic, huh?
Magique, hein ?
Sheldon, I'm disappointed.
Sheldon, je suis déçue.
As a brilliant man, you're entitled to a vice.
Comme tu es brillant, tu as droit a un vice.
I could understand frequenting an opium den...
Tu pourrais fréquenter une fumerie d'opium
...or hunting your fellow man for sport.
ou faire une chasse à l'homme.
But this? Lame-o.
Mais ça ? C‘est nase.
A, comic books employ storytelling through sequential art...
Les BD utilisent une forme d'art séquentiel
...a medium that dates back 17,000 years to the cave paintings of Lascaux...
qu'on trouvait il y a 17 000 ans dans les grottes de Lascaux
...and B, you play the harp, like that's cool.
et tu joues dela harpe, comme si c‘était cool.
Can I help you find anything?
Tu cherches quelque chose ?
A comic that depicts a woman whose bosom can't be used as a flotation device.
Une BD où les seins dela femme ne lui servent pas de flotteurs.
Sorry. Most of the guys who come in here like big boobs.
Les types qui viennent ici aiment les gros seins.
A couple of them have big boobs.
Certains d‘entre eux ont de gros seins.
The new Warlords of Ka'a expansion pack is out.
Le nouveau Guerriers de Ka‘a est sorti.
A new one? Unbelievable.
Un nouveau ? Incroyable.
Theyjust keep making up more cheesy monsters...
Ils n'arrêtent pas de créer d'horribles monstres,
...slapping them on cards and selling them at 25 bucks a pop.
de les mettre sur des cartes pour les vendre 25 $ chacune.
It's like a secret tax on guys who can't get laid.
C‘est une taxe secrète sur les types qui ne baisent pas.
They're not even trying. Remember the Satanimals pack with the Hellephant?
Ils n'essaient pas. Tu te rappelles les Satanimals avec l‘Hellephant?
Absurd. What was he, a bad elephant who died and went to hell?
Un éléphant méchant qui est mort et est allé en enfer ?
What could an elephant possibly do that would cause him eternal damnation?
Que peut faire un éléphant pour mériter la damnation éternelle ?
"Wild West and Witches."
"Far West et Magiciens."
What kind of loser cares about a showdown...
Quel loser s‘intéresserait a un combat
...between Billy the Kid and the White Wizard of the North? Heh.
entre Billy the Kid et le Magicien blanc du Nord ?
A total loser.
Un loser total.
Obviously, a guy with a six-shooter beats an old man with a magic wand.
Un type avec un revolver bat un Vieux avec une baguette magique, normal.
Well, ho-- hold on.
Attends.
Uh, what if the wizard casts a helmet-of-confusion spell...
Et si le magicien jetait un sort ”casque de confusion"
...on Billy the Kid's cowboy hat?
sur le chapeau de Billy the Kid ?
What? Please. This is Billy the Kid we're talking about.
Arrête. On parle de Billy the Kid.
The wizard would get shot before he could get out the words:
Le magicien serait abattu avant même d‘avoir dit :
"What the hell is Billy the Kid doing in the mystic realm of Ka'a?"
"Que fait Billy the Kid dans le royaume mystique de Ka‘a ?"
Leonard, ahem...
Leonard,
...what's the deal with Sheldon's friend Amy?
qu'est-ce qu'il y a entre Sheldon et Amy ?
-Are they a couple? -A couple of weirdos. Why?
- Ils sont en couple ? - Un couple de tarés. Pourquoi ?
Are you interested in Amy?
Tu t'intéresses à Amy ?
Well, I mean, she didn't look through me...
Elle ne m‘a pas regardé
...with soul-sucking, ball-shriveling hatred and contempt.
avec un regard de haine et un mépris insoutenables.
I like that in a woman.
Ça me plait chez une femme.
Could you run it by Sheldon ifl could ask her out?
Tu peux voir avec Sheldon si je peux l‘inviter ?
Sure, I guess.
Bien sûr.
Stuart, settle an argument for us.
Stuart, mets-nous d‘accord.
Who would win, Billy the Kid or the White Wizard?
Qui gagnerait, Billy the Kid ou le Magicien blanc ?
If I tell you that, I'm robbing you of the hours of fun you could have...
Si je te le dis, je te prive du plaisir que tu pourrais avoir
...for the magical, rootin'-tootin low price of 24.95.
pour le prix magique de 24,95 $.
-l'll take one. -Mm. Make it two.
-J'en prends un. - Mets-en deux.
I hate all of you and myself. Three.
Je vous déteste, et moi avec. Trois.
I'll ring it up.
Je vais encaisser.
Like shooting nerds in a barrel.
C‘était couru d‘avance.
Hey, can I talk to you about something? It's a little awkward.
Je peux te parler d'un truc un peu délicat ?
I know what this is about.
Je sais ce que c'est.
Given the professional standstill you're at...
Vu ton manque d'activité professionnelle,
...you're wondering if this is the appropriate time...
tu te demandes si c‘est le bon moment
...to abandon your research and focus on teaching.
pour abandonner la recherche et faire de l‘enseignement.
Yes.
Oui.
And ifl may suggest, consider changing disciplines.
Si tu veux mon avis, change de discipline.
Yeah, to the humanities. Perhaps, history.
Les lettres. L‘histoire, peut—ètre.
One of the advantages of teaching history...
L'avantage d‘enseigner l‘histoire,
...is that you don't have to create things.
c‘est que tu n'as pas a créer des trucs.
You know, you just have to remember stuff that happened...
Tu dois juste te souvenir d'événements qui ont eu lieu
...and then parrot it back.
et les répéter comme un perroquet.
You could have fun with that.
Ça peut être marrant.
Yeah, that's not it.
Ce n‘est pas ça.
Stuart's kind of interested in Amy.
Stuart s‘intéresse à Amy.
Well, of course, he is. She's very interesting.
C‘est normal. Elle est très intéressante.
Did you know, when she was 14...
Tu savais qu'à l'âge de 14 ans,
...she severed the webbing between her own toes?
elle a sectionné Ia palmature entre ses orteils ?
He wanted me to find out if you'd have a problem with him asking her out.
Il voulait savoir si ça te dérange qu'il l'invite à sortir avec lui.
Well, I'm not sure how to respond, Leonard.
Je ne sais pas quoi répondre.
I mean, I don't own Amy. You can't own a person.
Amy ne m'appartient pas. On ne possède pas les gens.
At least, not since....
Du moins, pas depuis...
1863.
1863.
President Lincoln freed the....
Le président Lincoln a libéré les…
The slaves. Come on, Leonard, if you're gonna teach history...
Les esclaves. Si tu dois enseigner l‘histoire,
...these are the kind of facts you'll have to know.
c‘est le genre de choses que tu devrais savoir.
You know what? Never mind. I'm gonna tell him it's okay to ask her out.
Laisse tomber. Je vais lui dire que tu es d‘accord.
The question is moot. There is no way that Stuart...
C‘est discutable. C‘est impossible que Stuart,
...an impoverished peddler of picture books...
un pauvre vendeur de BD,
...would be at all appealing to Amy Farrah Fowler...
plaise à Amy Farrah Fowler,
...a noted neurobiologist...
une éminente neurobiologiste,
...capable of performing surgery on her own feet...
capable de faire une opération
...with nothing but nitrous oxide from cans of whipped cream as anesthesia.
avec de l‘hémioxyde d‘azote issu de crème fouettée comme anesthésiant.
All right, but for the record...
Bien, mais pour info,
...I checked in with you to see how you'd feel about it.
je voulais savoir ce que tu en pensais.
Fine. The record shall so reflect.
Bien. Tu le sais maintenant.
Now, getting back to the problem at hand...
Pour en revenir au problème,
...what to do with a washed-up experimental physicist.
que faire d'un physicien expérimental fichu.
I am not washed-up.
Je ne suis pas fichu.
Oh, Leonard.
Leonard.
Lots of people love you and want to help you...
Beaucoup de gens t'aiment et veulent t'aider,
...but they can't until you admit the problem.
mais il faut que tu admettes le problème.
Ugh. Well, ladies, we killed the bottle.
On a fait un sort àla bouteille.
-I had half a glass. -I didn't have any.
-J'ai eu un demi-verre. - Et moi, rien.
Okay, don'tjudge me.
Ne me jugez pas.
So, what do you wanna do? Go to the movies, go dancing...
Vous voulez aller au ciné, danser,
...lay down for a little bit? Ahem.
vous allonger un peu ?
Or we play...
On peutjouer
...Travel Twister.
a Travel Twister.
Amy, really? Twister?
Quoi ? Twister ?
Excuse me, I've passed many an enjoyable evening playing this game.
J'ai passé de super soirées ajouer a ce jeu.
And I'm sure it's a lot more exciting when you play with other people.
C‘est sûrement beaucoup plus sympa quand on joue a plusieurs.
What do you say, bestie? We can do shirts and skins. I'm shirts. Called it.
On pourrait faire un strip si on perd. Moi, je gagne toujours.
I'm too small for Twister. And roller coasters.
Je suis trop petite pour le Twister. Et le grand huit.
And sitting with my feet on the floor.
Et pour toucher le sol avec mes pieds une fois assise.
Hope you enjoyed the prenatal cigarettes, mom.
J'espère que tu as apprécié les cigarettes prénatales, maman.
Hey, my mom smoked pot when she was pregnant with me...
Ma mère fumait de l‘herbe quand elle était enceinte de moi
...and I turned outjust fine.
etje vais bien.
Hey, look, I have peach schnapps. Thank God.
J'ai de l'eau-de-vie de pêche. Dieu merci.
-Guys, something happened. -What's wrong?
- Il est arrivé un truc. - Quoi ?
I think a boy likes me.
Je crois qu'un garçon m‘apprécie.
"Hi. It's Stuart. We met at the comic book store.
“C‘est Stuart. On s‘est rencontrés au magasin de BD.
l was wondering if you'd like to get coffee sometime. It's okay if you say no.
Voudrais-tu prendre un café ? Tu peux dire non.
It might be the kick in the pants I need to start taking Zoloft."
Je comprendrais qu'il est temps que je prenne des antidépresseurs."
Amy, you little vixen.
Amy, petite coquine.
Just working it under all those layers of wool and polyester.
Tu caches bien ton jeu sous ces couches de laine et de polyester.
What are you gonna do? Doesn't he know you have a boyfriend?
Il ne sait pas que tu as un petit ami ?
Oh, she doesn't have a boyfriend, she has a Sheldon.
Ce n‘est pas un petit ami, c‘est Sheldon.
-So do you like Stuart? -I don't know.
- Tu aimes bien Stuart ? - Je n'en sais rien.
He's nice. He's funny. He has the sallow-drawn countenance...
Il est sympa, drôle. Il a un teint cireux
...associated with an overactive thyroid gland. That's kind of hot.
associé à une thyroïde hyperactive. C‘est plutôt sexy.
Look, sweetie, we all love Sheldon, but you've been with him over a year now.
On aime tous Sheldon, mais ça fait plus d'un an que tu es avec lui.
If it's not going anywhere, what does it hurt to look around?
Si ça ne mène nulle part, quel mal y a-t-il a regarder autour ?
Yeah, I guess they're not engaged like me and Howie.
Ils ne sont pas fiancés comme Howie et moi.
For what it's worth, engaged people can look around too. Lot of options out there.
Les fiancés peuvent aussi regarder autour d'eux. Il y ale choix.
Where's Stuart?
Où est Stuart ?
Out.
Sorti.
-Who are you? -l'm Dale. He left me in charge.
- Qui es-tu ? - Dale. Il m‘a laissé le magasin.
-Really? -Yeah.
- C‘est vrai ? - Oui.
I don't get it either.
Je ne comprends pas non plus.
I wanna return this Wild West and Witches Ka'a expansion pack.
Je veux rendre le Far West et les Magiciens Ka‘a.
Sorry, I don't do returns. They're hard.
Je ne m'occupe pas de ça. C‘est dur.
Sure, sure.
Je comprends.
-Uh, when will Stuart be back? -I don't know. He went out for coffee.
- Stuart rentre quand ? - Il est sorti prendre un café.
With agirl.
Avec une fille.
You okay?
Çava?
Am I okay? Leonard, I'm on a lifelong trajectory...
Je suis sur une longue trajectoire
...that includes a Nobel Prize and cities named after me.
qui comprend un prix Nobel et des villes portant mon nom.
All four wisdom teeth fit comfortably in my mouth without need of extraction...
Mes dents de sagesse n‘ont pas besoin d‘être arrachées
...and my bowel movements run like a German train schedule.
et mon transit intestinal est ponctuel comme un train allemand.
Am I okay?
Est-ce que ça va ?
I'm okay too.
Moi aussi, ça va.
Wild Bill Witchcock.
Wild Bill Witchcock.
A tribe of Abra-Comanches.
Une tribu d'Abra-Comanches.
Flaming Spittoon.
Satané Crachoir.
And for the record, I'm very disappointed in you, cowpokes.
Pour info, vous me décevez beaucoup, cow—boys.
We're playing our inaugural round of Wild West and Witches...
On inaugure Far West et Magiciens,
...and I'm the only one who bothered to dress for the occasion.
etje suis le seul a m'être déguisé pour l‘occasion.
We're not wearing cowboy hats, Sheldon. It looks ridiculous.
On ne porte pas de chapeau de cow-boy. C‘est ridicule.
And I suppose my boots and spurs are ridiculous too?
Mes bottes et mes éperons sont ridicules également ?
HOWARD & LEONARD: Yeah. RAJESH: Incredibly so.
- Oui. - Absolument.
Did it look ridiculous when we got the Satanimals pack...
J‘avais l‘air ridicule quand on a acheté les Satanimals
...and l dressed up as a Beelzebobcat?
et que je me suis déguisé en Beelzebobcat ?
HOWARD & LEONARD: Yeah. RAJESH: Incredibly so.
- Oui. - Absolument.
All right, fine. Let's just play.
Bien. On joue.
We should go easy on him. Amy's out with Stuart tonight.
Il faut être sympa avec lui. Amy sort avec Stuart ce soir.
Wait a minute. Are you telling me...
Tu es en train de me dire
...that Sheldon's patented blend of condescension and no sex...
que le mélange de condescendance et d‘absence de sexe de Sheldon
...isn't enough to hold on to a woman?
ne suffit pas à retenir une femme ?
Cluck. Cluck. Cluck. What are we, ladies at a quilting bee?
On est des bonnes femmes a une réunion de couture ?
Or are we men playing a fantasy card game...
Ou des hommes qui jouent à un jeu de cartes
...set in a magical frontier town?
qui se déroule dans une Ville frontière magique ?
Sorry.
Désolé.
Creepy Tepee.
Affreux Tipi.
Annie Ogly.
Annie Ogly.
Hocus Pocus Pocahontas.
Hocus Pocus Pocahontas.
And mayl point out, it is the three of you...
C‘est vous trois
...who are obsessed with Stuart and Amy, not me.
qui êtes obsédés par Stuart et Amy, pas moi.
I think you need to ask yourselves who's really being ridiculous here.
Demandez-vous qui est ridicule ici.
-lt's you. -You are.
- C‘est toi. - Toi.
Hey, guys, check it out.
Regardez.
The deluxe limited edition Wild West and Witches expansion pack...
L‘édition limitée de luxe de Far West et Magiciens
...in the signed and numbered collector's tin.
dans la boite collector signée et numérotée.
Come on, no. We just bought the regular pack.
Non. On a acheté lejeu normal.
Ooh. A sheriff's badge. Ha, ha.
Un badge de shérif.
Yeah, it's also a wand.
C‘est aussi une baguette magique.
With a hologram? Nice.
Avec un hologramme ? Super.
Hey, do you see this?
Tu as vu ça?
I'm in the matrix, Leonard, I see everything.
Je suis dans la matrice, je vois tout.
You gotta be kidding me. You friended Stuart on Facebook?
Tu plaisantes. Tu as mis Stuart dans tes amis sur Facebook ?
-I thought you didn't like Facebook. -Don't be silly.
- Tu n‘aimes pas Facebook. - Ne sois pas stupide.
I'm a fan of anything that tries to replace actual human contact.
J'aime tout ce qui essaie de remplacer le contact humain.
Please. You're looking at Facebook to find out how their date went.
Tu regardes Facebook pour voir comment leur soirée s‘est passée.
Really? You think I care if a man...
Tu crois que ça m‘intéresse de savoir qu'un homme
...what, "Shared a pumpkin latte with a dynamite lady"?
"a partagé un café au lait àla citrouille avec une bombe" ?
-You're so full of it. -You're free to believe whatever you like.
- Absolument. - Crois ce que tu veux.
And unfriend Rajesh Koothrappali.
Je retire Rajesh Koothrappali de mes amis.
You unfriended me? Seriously?
C‘est vrai ?
Oh, yeah. Now he's gonna miss all those great updates like:
Il va rater les super mises ajour du style:
"I can't believe I waited this long...
"Comment ai-je pu attendre aussi longtemps pour faire mon pot pourri."
Why don't you acknowledge you have feelings for Amy...
Pourquoi ne pas admettre que tu as des sentiments pour Amy
...and don't want her going out with other men?
et que tu ne veux pas qu'elle sorte avec d'autres hommes ?
And unfriend Leonard Hofstadter.
Je retire Leonard Hofstadter de mes amis.
Here's a radical thought. Go old school. Challenge Stuart to a fight.
Joue-Ia a l‘ancienne. Propose a Stuart de vous battre.
Nothing makes the ladies hotter than two skinny white guys...
Rien n'excite plus une femme que deux Blancs rachitiques
...swatting at each other with their eyes closed.
se tapant dessus les yeux fermés.
And unfriend Howard Wolowitz.
Je retire Howard Wolowitz de mes amis.
That's all of us. Can I use the laptop?
Je peux utiliser le portable ?
-Why? -l have to buy that stupid collector's tin.
- Pourquoi ? - Pour acheter la boite collector.
PENNY: Who do we love? -Penny.
- Qui aimes-tu ? - Penny.
Hello, Sheldon. Come on in.
Bonjour, Sheldon. Entré.
-Thank you. -What's up?
- Merci. - Qu‘est—ce qu'il y a ?
I came to ask if you would like to go on a date with me.
Tu aimerais sortir avec moi ?
I'm sorry, what?
Pardon, quoi ?
A date. You and me.
Une sortie. Toi et moi.
Dining, dancing, perhaps you'd like to take in a prizefight.
Dîner, disco, un match de boxe, si tu veux.
Ugh, God, are you trying to make Amyjealous?
Tu essaies de rendre Amyjalouse ?
No. Why is everyone so obsessed with Amy and Stuart?
Non. Pourquoi tout le monde veut savoir si Amy et Stuart
Whether or not they may be having more pumpkin lattes or intercourse tonight.
boivent du café au lait àla citrouille
Okay, listen to me.
Ecoute-moi.
Playing games is not gonna help get Amy back.
Ce n‘est pas en te moquant d‘Amy que tu la récupéreras.
lam not trying to get her back.
Je n'essaie pas de la récupérer.
But out of curiosity, what is a way?
Mais par curiosité, comment on fait ?
All right, honey, let me tell you a story.
Je vais te raconter une histoire.
There was a guy I liked, and I never told him how I felt.
Il y a un gars a qui je n'ai jamais dit ce que je ressentais.
Eventually, he started going out with someone else and I always regretted it.
Il est sorti avec une autre etje l'ai toujours regretté.
Do you see where I'm going with this?
Tu vois où je veux en venir ?
-I believe I do. -Hmm.
Je crois que oui.
I'm the guy.
C‘est moi, le type.
You're not the guy.
Ce n‘est pas toi.
Are you sure? That would explain so much.
Tu en es sûre ? Ça expliquerait beaucoup de choses.
Your constant presence in my apartment...
Ta présence constante dans mon appart‘,
...that baffling dalliance with Leonard just to be near me...
ce badinage déroutant avec Leonard pour être prés de moi,
...the way you call me sweetie all the time.
cette façon de m‘appeler "mon chou" tout le temps.
-I call everyone sweetie. -You tramp.
- J‘appelle tout le monde comme ça. - Allumeuse.
Look, Sheldon, all I'm saying is strap on a pair and go talk to Amy.
Si tu en as une paire, va parler à Amy.
Strap on a pair? Wait. Of what, skates?
Une paire de quoi ? De rollers ?
Oh, sweetie, you are so not the guy.
Tu n'es vraiment pas le type.
If you're bored, you can go. I understand.
Si tu t'ennuies, tu peux partir. Je comprends.
No, I'm having a nice time.
Non,je passe un bon moment.
Excuse me. Excuse me. Pardon me. Excuse me.
Excusez-moi. Pardon.
Pardon me. Excuse me.
Pardon.
-Hi, Stuart. -Hi, Sheldon.
- Salut, Stuart. - Salut, Sheldon.
Pardon me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Excusez-moi.
Sheldon, what are you doing here?
Qu‘est—ce que tu fais la ?
The thought of you sitting in a darkened theater...
Ça me dégoûte de t'imaginer assise dans un cinéma sombre
...with a character like Stuart is repellent.
avec quelqu'un comme Stuart.
-No offense, Stuart. -None taken.
- Ne te vexe pas, Stuart. - Pas du tout.
Although repellent is kind of a strong word.
Mais le terme dégoût est un peu fort.
I'm sorry this causes you discomfort...
Désolée que ça te mette mal a l‘aise,
...but based on the currently established parameters of our relationship...
mais en se basant sur les paramètres actuels de notre relation,
...I can put myself in any repellent situation I want.
je peux me mettre dans la situation dégoûtante que je veux.
Anything else?
Autre chose ?
I believe I would like to alter the paradigm of our relationship.
J'aimerais modifier le paradigme de notre relation.
I'm listening.
Je t'écoute.
With the understanding that nothing changes whatsoever...
En partant du principe que rien ne change,
...physical or otherwise...
physiquement ou autrement,
...I would not object to us no longer characterizing you...
je ne serais pas contre le fait de ne plus te définir
...as "not my girlfriend."
comme "pas mon amie".
Interesting. Now try it without the quadruple negative.
Intéressant. Répéte-le sans utiliser le quadruple négatif.
You're being impossible.
Tu es impossible.
Hi, Stuart.
Salut, Stuart.
Amy...
Amy,
...will you be my girlfriend?
tu veux bien être ma petite amie ?
-Yes. -Well, that's enough of that.
- Oui. - Bon, ça suffit.
Sorry to interrupt. You two enjoy your date.
Désolé pour le dérangement. Amusez-vous bien.
Here's a dollar for your troubles. Get yourself some Sour Patch Kids.
Voici un dollar pour la peine. Va t'acheter des bonbons.
Excuse me. Excuse me. Pardon me.
Excusez-moi. Pardon.
Other than you taking your relationship to the next level with another guy...
Hormis le fait que tu es passé à l‘étape supérieure avec un autre,
...this was nice.
c‘était sympa.
Yes, well, thanks for seeing me to my door.
Merci de m‘avoir raccompagnée.
Oh, you're welcome.
Pas de quoi.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Amy ? Amy ? Amy ?
Let's wrap things up out there.
Finissez-en.
SHELDON: Take the hint, Stuart. The lady said good night.
Tu as entendu. La dame t‘a dit bonne nuit.
How did you get into my apartment?
Comment es-tu entré chez moi ?
Wow. Is that the kind of nagging I can expect now that you're my girlfriend?
C‘est a ça que je dois m'attendre maintenant que tu es ma copine ?
Good thing I drew this up.
Heureusement que j'ai écrit ça.
What's that?
Quoi donc ?
I present to you the relationship agreement.
Je te présente le contrat de notre relation.
A binding covenant that, in its 31 pages, enumerates, iterates and codifies...
Un contrat de 31 pages qui énumère, réitère et codifie
...the rights and responsibilities of Sheldon Lee Cooper...
les droits et responsabilités de Sheldon Lee Cooper,
...here and after known as "the boyfriend"...
dénommé ”le petit ami",
...and Amy Farrah Fowler, here and after known as "the girlfriend."
et d‘Amy Farrah Fowler, dénommée ”la petite amie".
It's so romantic.
Comme c‘est romantique !
Mutual indemnification always is.
Le dédommagement mutuel l‘est toujours.
Why don't you start perusing while I set up my notary stamp.
Commence ale lire pendant que je cherche mon sceau.
"Section 5: Hand-holding.
"Section 5 : Se tenir la main.
Hand-holding is only allowed under the following circumstances.
On ne peut se tenir la main que dans les circonstances suivantes.
A, either party is in danger of falling off a cliff, precipice or ledge.
Une partie est sur le point de tomber d‘une falaise ou d'un précipice.
B, either party is deserving of a hearty handshake after winning a Nobel Prize.
Une partie mérite une poignée de mains chaleureuse pour le prix Nobel.
C, moral support during flu shots."
Soutien moral pendant une piqûre."
-Seems a bit restrictive. -Yeah, well, feel free to retain a lawyer.
- C‘est un peu restrictif. - Tu peux prendre un avocat.
Penny, I said, "Right hand, red."
J'ai dit : ”Main droite, rouge."
Yeah, I heard you. I got red. Ahem.
J'ai entendu. J'ai le rouge.
Bernadette...
Bernadette,
...left foot, yellow.
pied gauche, jaune.
We should play limbo next. No one beats me at limbo.
On devraitjouer au limbo. Je suis imbattable.
That's my boyfriend.
C‘est mon petit ami.
It's open.
C‘est ouvert.
I got a splinter.
J'ai une écharde.
What do you want me to do about it?
Qu‘est—ce que tu veux que j‘y fasse ?
Relationship Agreement Section 4: Boo-boos and Ouchies.
Section 4 du contrat : Petis bobos.
You have to take care of it.
Tu dois me soigner.
lshould've gotten a lawyer.
J'aurais dû prendre un avocat.
Looks like it's just us playing.
On n‘est que deux ajouer, alors.
Penny?
Penny ?
-Penny, we're out of wine. -You should probably drive.
- Il n‘y a plus de vin. - Tu devrais conduire.
[English - us - an]
[French]